https://www.lib.ncsu.edu/privacy

skip to Main Navigation
skip to Main Content
skip to Footer
Accessibility feedback
NC State HomeCOVID-19 UpdatesResources Campus DirectoryMyPack PortalCampus MapLibrariesCampus ResourcesUniversity HousingNC State DiningBookstoresWolfline BusesCalendarDiversityAcademic ResourcesUndergraduate AdmissionsAcademic DepartmentsWolfWare/MoodleGlobal EngagementDistance EducationAcademic CalendarOther ResourcesStudent Services CenterCashier's OfficeRegistration and RecordsScholarships and Financial AidCareer Development CenterNC State Help Desk Outreach and EngagementGivingNC State NewsGraduate SchoolGmail AccessNC State Social Media
What to know about the Libraries: Winter Break
Privacy Statement
Data is created and collected each time you use certain Libraries services, technology, and this website. In accordance with NC State University’s Privacy Statement and consonant with the values described below, the Libraries stores and analyzes some of this data to continually improve and adapt our services and resources.
Commitment to Privacy and Confidentiality
The NC State University Libraries upholds the privacy, confidentiality, and intellectual freedom of our users as core values as described in the American Library Association’s Code of Ethics. The Libraries does not grant unauthorized access to or disclose any identifiable library record, as specified in NCSU RUL 02.61.02 and North Carolina General Statutes 125 § 18-19.
Security Compliance
The NC State University Libraries complies with federal, state, and institutional regulations regarding the security of personal user data and library records. Guidelines and procedures for securely storing and transferring sensitive data are determined based on NC State University’s Data Sensitivity Framework.
Data Collection and Use
Library Systems
The NC State University Libraries uses and stores moderately sensitive Personally Identifiable Information (PII) for operations and services, such as checking out a book or laptop. Examples of this data are first and last name, email address/Unity ID, student ID, and university status and affiliation. De-identified library circulation records are securely stored for ongoing collection management and service improvement. We also collect and utilize data related to Libraries workshops, programs, and use of spaces, technology, and other services for the purpose of taking attendance, program evaluation, and tracking trends. We maintain the confidentiality of all the information that we receive.
University Systems
Many of the applications used for library operations retrieve personal data from systems that are maintained and secured by the university. As a contributing partner to the learning and research mission and goals of the university, the Libraries may share de-identified, generalized, and/or aggregate data with authorized entities for ongoing assessment and improvement.
To assist with the assessment and purchasing of relevant software, the university uses the software package LabStats which tracks the use of applications on the library’s patron computers. Data collected within this system, such as Unity ID and average session time, is only available to authorized NC State University staff.
Third-Party Services
Certain collections, such as electronic journals and databases, are provided by third-party publishers and vendors that may collect PII and use it according to their respective policies.
In addition, the Libraries uses the following third-party services on this website.
Google Analytics
The Libraries’ website uses Google Analytics to capture and analyze web statistics.  The information gathered is used to improve web services for site users. Google Analytics uses a browser cookie to gather and process data related to your browsing behavior on library websites. Data typically collected include network location; hostname; web pages requested; referring web page; browser used; screen resolution; date and time. No personal information is stored within cookies. If you choose, you may opt out by turning off cookies in your browser preferences. For more information on Google Analytics, visit www.google.com/analytics.
AddEvent
The “Add to Calendar” button for Libraries events, programs, and workshops is provided by a third-party vendor called AddEvent. AddEvent uses browser cookies and Pixel Tags and collects personal data that includes information such as IP address. For more information, visit https://www.addevent.com/terms and https://www.addevent.com/privacy.
Occuspace
The Libraries uses the product Occuspace to report how many people are in certain spaces throughout the day. This allows users to assess the approximate availability of seating in those spaces. The Occuspace “beacon” uses Bluetooth and WiFi technology to analyze radio frequency signal data in the area from any electronic device (e.g., laptop, phone, Fitbit, etc.) that has Bluetooth or WiFi turned on. Data collected includes MAC address, signal strength indicator, and time stamp. The MAC address is encrypted on the Occuspace beacon before being irreversibly hashed. Hashed data is then sent to Occuspace servers and deleted from the beacon. No PII is collected or transmitted in this process. If you do not want the Occuspace beacon to observe your electronic device, you can turn off your device’s Bluetooth and WiFi. For more information, visit https://occuspace.io/public/assets/occuPrivacyPolicy.pdf.
Questions
If you have questions about library data privacy, please contact Rob Rucker at rrrucker@ncsu.edu or 919-513-3657.
NC State University's Office of Information Technology recommends the use of these sound password practices to protect your data.
Top of page
×
